# Astrid Countee, M.A.

cell: 832-477-3298 email: astridwcountee@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/astridcountee/ https://github.com/astridw portfolio: http://astrid.link

I am an experienced professional that can analyze data, conduct user research, manage a project, and program code. I possess a unique mix of soft skills and technical abilities due to my dual background in social science and computer programming. I am best when I am working in an interdisciplinary team that allows me to make the most of all my skills. I am even better if I am leading it.

## **EDUCATION**

**The Iron Yard Academy**—Rails engineering (see my portfolio here <a href="http://astrid.link">http://astrid.link</a>) also Rails Girls Coach, volunteer at Space City JS conference, volunteer at SQLSaturday.

**University of Houston** – MA, Applied Anthropology: Ethnographer, User Researcher, Cultural Theorist. Invited to health fairs in the Houston area to speak on my thesis topic, Diabetes and Chronic Disease, in 2013.

**Baylor University** – BA, Psychology with emphasis on cognition.

## **SOFTWARE SKILLS AND LANGUAGES**

- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- HTML, CSS, Sass
- JavaScript
- Git, Github
- Responsive Web Design
- Ajax
- Bootstrap, Middleman

- Pry
- JQuery
- JSON APIs, REST
- Unit Testing
- UX/UI Design
- Heroku
- Agile Development
- AWS
- SQL

- SSMS
- Excel
- Access
- R
- Project Management
- Rapid Assessment
- Linux OS
- Python
- SaltStack

## **PUBLICATIONS**

**Masters Thesis:** African Americans of Creole Identity Living with Diabetes and Hypertension in Houston, December 2011

**Self-Help(Career):** From Degree to Paycheck: A Guide For the Liberal Arts Grad, September 2015

**The Inquisitive Anthropologist:** A blog that talks about Social Science, Technology, and my journey as a Software Developer and Anthropologist(<a href="http://ianthro.com">http://ianthro.com</a>)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Quality Assurance/Devops Engineer (contract)**

Hewlett-Packard

#### **April 2015-Present**

Hp has created a flagship software as a service product called HP Touchpoint Manager meant to help small to medium sized businesses control their devices. Still in its infancy, HP needs more developers to add to the project as it scales. To solve this I have participated in:

- QA integration Testing, creation of code for User Behavior Testing
- Writing Linux commands to manage cloud based computing in AWS
- Create Python scripts for configuration management in Saltstack

I have gleaned skills on what it takes to scale a company, and the intricacies of working on a large software development team that is distributed around the globe. I have learned skills such as testing, QA, strategy for checking in code, management of development environments, Linux and configuration management.

#### **Software Developer**

Freelance

## **January 2015-Present**

Startups, small business owners, and individuals come to me when they have a need for a software developer to build technical solutions. To solve this I:

- Create custom web solutions using Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Manage Data using Access, Excel, SQL
- Create Wordpress sites
- Utilize Social Media Marketing Consulting
- Work with health related startups: The Docgraph Journal, Prenovate, Obella Be

I have gained a breadth of software experience. I have created apps in rails, worked on data analysis using sql, created landing pages and portfolios, and worked as a consultant and advisor.

### **Business Data Analyst—Technical Training and Development**

Williams Company

September 2013- July 2014

The Williams Company lacked visibility over their regulatory compliance training completion status. Logistical challenges and a broad geography made it difficult to verify if engineers completed the training in a timely manner. To solve the issue I:

- Constructed and presented a metric analysis of company training programs to internal stakeholders
- Created Williams first ever Technical Training Database to track company metrics across North America
- Contributed to design team for internal website, participated in usability testing of eLearning courses

As a result, the Williams Company acquired visibility over their global compliance training status for their **5000+** employees and reduced legal liability.

#### Data Analyst/Supervisor

TGS Geophysical Company

March 2011 – September 2013

TGS acquired a production data company in an effort to diversify their client library. The team that created the product left the company after the acquisition. TGS needed new members to learn the product and take over full development and production. To solve this problem I:

- 1st Supervisor for this product, improved data warehousing, managed software development life cycle
- Designed and co-created UI for analyst team that cut product delivery time by 50%
- Grew QA team by 200% within 6 months
- Shortened turnaround for customers by 70% by developing close relationships with sales, marketing, customer support and development team
- 1st multi-million dollar contract for this product

As a result, I was able learn sql development on the job and took over as the primary data analyst. I grew my team to 4 additional analysts and took over as supervisor. Due to our work, TGS acquired a nearly **Multi-million** dollar contract with Chesapeake Energy company for access to our production data library.

#### **Upstream Well Data Supervisor**

TGS Geophysical Company

**December 2006 – March 2011** 

TGS was scaling very quickly when I started and needed staff that could assimilate to their needs. The goal of this division was to grow a **1 million** well data set from where they were at the time, around **160,000** wells digitized.

- Strategically managed between 50 and 70 employees and 4 coordinators
- Increased monthly output while cutting overtime by 80% by implementing strategic workflows
- Grew staff by 20% and trained all current staff while maintaining and exceeding monthly goals
- Created mentorship program to all staff members to accelerate their careers

Orcalca

During my time at TGS we reached over **1 million** wells in our library. My team was able to grow **3x** while also training in advanced well data products allowing us to charge **3 to 4 x's** more for those products.

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

#### Host of New Books in Anthropology, New Books Network

-I find and interview authors of recently published books related to anthropology

#### Trainee, MD Anderson Cancer Center: CRMH (Center for Research in Minority Health)

-I participated in research and analysis of survey data for health disparities research using SPSS. During my time there I also contributed to conferences on health disparities in Texas.

#### Rails Girls Coach, Rails Girls Houston

-I coached girls in a weekend workshop to create web applications with ruby on rails.

#### Transcriber, Surviving Katrina and Rita in Houston Project

-I helped to document survival stories of residents of the gulf coast in the wake of hurricanes Katrina and Rita

#### Emergency Center Volunteer, Ben Taub General Hospital

- I volunteered in the emergency center helping the patient advocates, stocking trauma rooms, and learning about how a level I trauma center manages its patients.

#### Mentor, Fruition Technology Labs

- I work with emerging companies by providing technical services and advice. Featured company (<a href="http://obellabe.com">http://obellabe.com</a>).

#### Organizer, One Million Cups

- One million cups works to create a community for entrepreneurs to share and grow in Houston

## **AWARDS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Featured story and video on The Iron Yard site (<a href="http://theironyard.com">http://theironyard.com</a>)
- Member of Golden Key National Honor Society (University of Houston)
- Special Topics Course created at UH based on my thesis (Family Talk and Chronic Disease)
- Member of American Psychological Association
- Co-organizer for Rails Girls Houston